<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>~ Welcome fellow Traveller ~</title>
    <link>//csabakiraly.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ~ Welcome fellow Traveller ~</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 14:44:49 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//csabakiraly.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude</title>
      <link>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/gratitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 14:44:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/gratitude/</guid>
      <description>In this day and world it&amp;rsquo;s easy to focus on things/experiences which you don&amp;rsquo;t have. Let&amp;rsquo;s go against the main-stream &amp;amp; look into what you already have. Gratitude is the state of being grateful; a positive emotional state in which one recognizes and appreciates all the wonders what one has received. Research shows, that taking time to experience gratitude or thankfulness can make you happier &amp;amp; both physically and emotionally healthier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//csabakiraly.eu/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 10:57:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//csabakiraly.eu/about/about/</guid>
      <description>At the moment I&amp;rsquo;m only available via online channels, you can reach me if you are looking for individual or group counseling, trainings or would like to discuss ideas about projects, I like to dream projects into reality. If you feel that you&amp;rsquo;d like to work together with me, let&amp;rsquo;s contact &amp;amp; discuss the details. I charge based on income levels, so if you are unemployed, student, or in a challenging financial situation, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me and we will find a way!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bio</title>
      <link>//csabakiraly.eu/bio/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 08:18:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//csabakiraly.eu/bio/bio/</guid>
      <description>EXPERIENCE Freelance Psychologist since 2017 Personal and group counseling in Hungarian and in English. Designing and providing training, videos, lectures in the following topics: stress management, exploring and instrumetalising values, setting personal goals and creating action plans for and achieving them, integration, mindfulness, positive psychology, psychological first-aid, modern technology and its impact on mental health.
 Part time Psychologist at HRC Group Hungary since 2019 Short psychological counseling in English and in Hungarian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//csabakiraly.eu/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//csabakiraly.eu/welcome/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>