<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on ~ Welcome fellow Traveller ~</title>
		<link>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on ~ Welcome fellow Traveller ~</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 14:44:49 +0200</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="//csabakiraly.eu/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Social Dilemma</title>
			<link>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/social-dilemma/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 14:44:49 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/social-dilemma/</guid>
			<description>A man just woke up from 50 years of hibernation. How could you describe to him what has changed in the world? We carry a device in our pocket which can access almost all the knowledge of mankind, yet we use it mainly to share cat photos. Sure sending &amp;amp; receiving feline pictures could be fun.
Let me ask you a question: Would you allow an invention to be legal which would kill 1,35 million people annually but raise the average life quality for the majority?</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A man just woke up from 50 years of hibernation. How could you describe to him what has changed in the world? We carry a device in our pocket which can access almost all the knowledge of mankind, yet we use it mainly to share cat photos.
Sure sending &amp; receiving feline pictures could be fun.</p>
<p>Let me ask you a question:
Would you allow an invention to be legal which would kill 1,35 million people annually but raise the average life quality for the majority?                                         (actual road traffic deaths by WHO)</p>
<p>The above point to an interesting layer of our technology usage: it can’t be judged without examining the underlying motivation and usage patterns meaning what, when &amp; how it is being used. It is indeed a miracle what could we achieve at our fingertips, but just like with any other tool, it could be abused as well.</p>
<p>May I ask you how much time do you spend on social media?
(do you dare to check it on your phone now?)</p>
<p>Why are you using it? When? How?</p>
<p>Have you ever logged in with a particular task in your mind and forgotten it and just scrolled through random material, selected by an AI to get your attention?
Since the very design of social media meant to be addictive, it’s quite easy to fall for their dopamine boosting design mechanism. Being a prisoner of an addictive loop could be viewed as mindless just the opposite of being mindful. How about claiming back your freedom? Let’s balance something with an addictive potential with its possible antidote counterpart.</p>
<p>After watching social dilemma and reading through their recommendations for developing a healthier relationship with social media technologies, namely:</p>
<ol>
<li>Turn off ALL notifications;</li>
<li>It’s nice to take a day off from technology on a weekly basis;</li>
<li>Never chose a recommended video, always chose YOURSELF;</li>
<li>Install extensions that remove recommendations (to avoid falling into the rabbit hole on Youtube);</li>
<li>Before you share, fact check, check the source, do that extra work;</li>
<li>Make sure to get all kinds of different information, in your own life;</li>
<li>Follow people that you disagree with;</li>
<li>No social media for young kids;</li>
<li>How much time do you WANT to spend on social media? Respect that.</li>
<li>If you can, delete your accounts. That way, we might have a few people ready to create a societal conversation that is not manipulated by the minds of the Silicon Valley.</li>
</ol>
<p>I realized that something I find very important is missing from the list and I should share with you an exercise I have designed when preparing my thesis.
I advised them to do a one minute meditation before logging into a particular social media site, like check in yourself before check into a social media platform: Furthermore you could continue exploring yourself during &amp; after the usage of that social media.</p>
<p>Gently observe &amp; approach yourself with a curious attitude e.g.: Can I allow myself an exercise of checking in with myself right now? How am I doing? How is my posture? My breath? Heartbeat? What bodily sensations Do I feel? Which emotions? What are my thoughts? What do I desire? What would I like to do at this moment?”</p>
<p>After logging in you may continue to observe your social media activity and your mind, body &amp; soul.</p>
<p>After log out again you may checking in with yourself. Just allow yourself to perceive whatever present within you.
How am I doing? How is my posture? My breath? Heartbeat? What bodily sensations Do I have? Which emotions? What are my thoughts? What do I desire? What would I like to do in this moment
Remember, there is no right &amp; wrong. Stay curious, open and keep exploring.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Taming thoughts &amp; emotions</title>
			<link>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/taming-thoughts-emotions/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 14:44:49 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/taming-thoughts-emotions/</guid>
			<description>In my understanding the only way to tame them is a twofold one :
accept &amp;amp; invite whatever arises listen to them and let them disappear
If I chase or flee they might get stuck in my psyche and in my body ! Circulation only goes smooth whenever I welcome &amp;amp; feel through anything coming up from my deep deep soul or void, without becoming this newcomer, meaning If I resist or identify with it, my flow might get stuck</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my understanding the only way to tame them is a twofold one :<br>
accept &amp; invite whatever arises
listen to them and let them disappear</p>
<p>If I chase or flee they might get stuck in my psyche and in my body !
Circulation only goes smooth whenever I welcome &amp; feel through anything coming up from my deep deep soul or void, without becoming this newcomer,
meaning If I resist or identify with it, my flow might get stuck</p>
<p>what if I just caught myself resisting one or perhaps identifying with another?
Step back &amp; gently observe this process; you might want to whisper to yourself:</p>
<p>„I am experiencing this.”</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>What is progress?</title>
			<link>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/progress/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 14:44:49 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/progress/</guid>
			<description>What is progress? Am I improving? Where do I go?
Some of our greatest minds lost their ways in the process of self-realization, stuck in a place where they have to constantly prove that they are worthy enough thus earning a right to exist. The endless search for approval could work as a barrier in their path. (isn’t it like licking your wound to heal it, but your tongue is too rough and ripping the surface again?</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What is progress? Am I improving? Where do I go?</p>
<p>Some of our greatest minds lost their ways in the process of self-realization, stuck in a place where they have to constantly prove that they are worthy enough thus earning a right to exist. The endless search for approval could work as a barrier in their path. (isn’t it like licking your wound to heal it, but your tongue is too rough and ripping the surface again?)
Don’t get me wrong: wanting to improve is a wonderful human trait. However it can be overdone in a way that eventually it might backfire and start poisioning. The engine for growing became corrupt and started handicapping itself.</p>
<p>Do you know someone like that? 
Think about what could be the cause?</p>
<p>Perhaps some undigested emotional charges from the past? Or is it the competitive individualistic culture of our time? The craving for constant growth? (But wait what If I don’t want to be a tumour)</p>
<p>What could help that person to outgrow their old habit? 
Is there a part of me which resembles that? How to heal it? Accept it? Integrate it? Can I contain my fears and desires? Do I have the capacity to hold my perfectly unperfect self? To treat every step of the journey as it is, leaving dualism of good &amp; evil behind.</p>
<p>What is the barrier between me and my unleashed potential right now? What could be the next step towards this destination?</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Gratitude</title>
			<link>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/gratitude/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 14:44:49 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//csabakiraly.eu/posts/gratitude/</guid>
			<description>In this day and world it&amp;rsquo;s easy to focus on things/experiences which you don&amp;rsquo;t have. Let&amp;rsquo;s go against the main-stream &amp;amp; look into what you already have. Gratitude is the state of being grateful; a positive emotional state in which one recognizes and appreciates all the wonders what one has received. Research shows, that taking time to experience gratitude or thankfulness can make you happier &amp;amp; both physically and emotionally healthier.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this day and world it&rsquo;s easy to focus on things/experiences which you don&rsquo;t have. Let&rsquo;s go against the main-stream &amp; look into what you already have.
Gratitude is the state of being grateful; a positive emotional state in which one recognizes and appreciates all the wonders what one has received. Research shows, that taking time to experience gratitude or thankfulness can make you happier &amp; both physically and emotionally healthier.</p>
<p>Take a moment to recall the last time you practiced gratitude. Let&rsquo;s continue this practice now and give 5 minutes to think about all the things you can be grateful for at this moment. They can be little - even minoculus - things/mundane, everday experiences or huge stuff/rare events. The point is to bring those to your mind and actively exercise being grateful.</p>
<p>How does it feel in your body? Any emotions came along?</p>
<p>If you liked it, you could practice it on a daily/weekly/whatever suits you basis. You might feel like writing down a list about all the things you are grateful for, you could even place the list in a place visible for you.<br>
Other way to pratice gratitude is to think about someone who you have not expressed your honest gratitude to lately and do it! The best if you can do it in person but it&rsquo;s ok to videochat/call/write/etc.</p>
<p>source: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jclp.22020">https://doi.org/10.1002/jclp.22020</a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
